Brian Salehi

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/ briansalehi

Address

Tehran, Iran

Brian Salehi

Software Engineer

Professional Summary I am a C and C++ programmer with expertise in Linux, having experience in C, C++, a few scripting languages, and development tools. I am interested in the open source movement and usually spend some of my spare time making open source tools or contributing to open source projects. I am looking forward to working in the Kernel development teams and projects.

Experiences

Arad Company

Iran (aradtechs.com) 05/2021 - 05/2022

Updated: July 21, 2022

Software Engineer

Contributed to four major projects including network programming, graphics programming, automation services, and continuous integration and delivery echo systems. I completed three projects on my own and contributed to two other major projects in two separate teams. Authored dozens of pages of reference manuals for internal knowledge sharing, and documented all major projects in the company both in web and in source versions.

Bio-informatics Laboratory (cooperation)

Poland (undisclosed)

Software Engineer, Consultant

08/2020 - 05/2022

Consulted for development of computational services and contributed to a few micro projects in bio-informatics applications. During this cooperation, many micro projects were successfully developed under my supervision and gratually landed on the laboratory's website. Further disclosure about this operation is not possible.

Sarmad Business Services (cooperation)

Iran (*sarmadbs.com*)

System Administrator, Database Specialist

04/2021 - 06/2021

Consulted for technical solutions, guided for administering Linux servers and maintaining database services, and finally authored many concise and comprehensive documentations for education of their staff. By the end of this cooperation, main business services of the company were set up and running under my supervision.

Training

International (milextone.ir)

Software Engineer, Technical Trainer

03/2019 - present

Trained 11 college to PhD graduate students in Iran, Germany, Poland, and the United States. Of all, a few successfully applied for scholarship of higher educational degrees, and others had job promotions. Fields of studies included Linux administration, Bash scripting, C, C++ and python programming, and a few development tools.

Manzoomeh Negaran Holdings

Iran (seller.ir)

Software Engineer, Database Specialist

06/2016 - 06/2017

Developed an entire web service and designed database of an industrial webstore caller Seller in a team of three. By the end of this cooperation, the website was fully functional.

Brian Salehi

Email

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

Tehran, Iran

Skills

Technical

C, C++, Python, Linux System Programming, Bash Scripting, Linux Administration, Qt, QML, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, x86_64 Assembly

Tools

Git, GCC, GDB, Nasm, Sanitizers, Valgrind Suite, Make, CMake Suite, Docker, Doxygen, Sphinx, UML, PlantUML, Vim, Latex

Education

MSc. of Computer Science	iau-tnb.ac.ir
Islamic Azad University	9/2021 - present

BSc. of Computer Science iauet.ac.ir
Islamic Azad University 9/2016 - 06/2021

Certificates

Fanavaran Anisa Ins.	anisa.co.ir
Linux Device Driver	2022
Embedded Linux	2022
Linux Application Development	2021
LPIC-3 Linux Security	2017
LPIC-2 Linux Networks	2016
LPIC-1 Linux Systems	2015

Languages

Persian (Native) English (Fluent) German (Basic)

Interests

Technical

Kernel hacking, embedded Linux, graphics programming, user interfaces, image processing, machine learning, software and hardware design, algorithms, mathematics, quantum mechanics, philosophy, psychiatry

Personal

Playing electric guitar, reading books, swimming, biking, running, hiking

References

Dr. Farhang Jaryani

fjayani@yahoo.com

Faculty of Computer Science, Arak University, Iran